<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pkrshnan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pkrshnan.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-28T16:51:25-04:00</updated><id>https://pkrshnan.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Pranav Krishnan</title><subtitle>Just your average software developer.
</subtitle><author><name>Pranav Krishnan</name></author><entry><title type="html">Clearing the Current Row in Vim</title><link href="https://pkrshnan.com/replace-current-row-vim" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clearing the Current Row in Vim" /><published>2021-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://pkrshnan.com/replace-current-row-vim</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pkrshnan.com/replace-current-row-vim">&lt;p&gt;Today I learned something really useful which started saving me a lot of time in vim. Up until recently, whenever I had to replace the content of the current row in a file, I had to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go into Normal Mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; to delete the current row’s contents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to previous row, hit &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; followed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start typing relevant content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, recently I realized that there is a default key-bind of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;, which will clear the content of the current row and put you into insert mode at the correct indentation level. The workflow then becomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go into Normal Mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; to clear row’s contents and go into insert mode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start typing relevant content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may seem like marginal improvements, it’s one less step which adds up over time. Hope this helped!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pranav Krishnan</name></author><category term="til" /><category term="vim" /><summary type="html">Today I learned something really useful which started saving me a lot of time in vim. Up until recently, whenever I had to replace the content of the current row in a file, I had to: Go into Normal Mode Use dd to delete the current row’s contents Go to previous row, hit A followed by Enter Start typing relevant content</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maplestory: A Classic With Modern Charm</title><link href="https://pkrshnan.com/maplestory" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maplestory: A Classic With Modern Charm" /><published>2021-04-12T15:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T15:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://pkrshnan.com/maplestory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pkrshnan.com/maplestory">&lt;p&gt;Maplestory is a massively multiplayer online role playing game (MMORPG), that was originally created for Korea and was quickly followed up by a Global release. The main premise of the game is that you start by playing one of 40+ classes, working towards trying to get stronger and eventually teaming up with fellow players in order to take down the “big bad”. Classic MMORPG stuff. There’s a lot of training, bossing and tons of social interaction involved in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game has been around for nearly two decades now, and I personally have been playing it on and off for more than a decade. It’s crazy to think how much my life has changed since I first started playing it, and how it’s sort of been a constant in my life throughout the past 11 years. There’s a lot to unpack about why it’s still around after all this time, but the main points I’ll cover are the charm, the content, and the daily questing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-charm&quot;&gt;The Charm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maplestory is a 2D side scrolling game, meaning the environment shifts as you move left, right, up and down, but there is no forward and backward movement whatsoever. Each character has their unique set of skills that are designed for their storyline and overall archetype. The game really leans into the idea of wonderful 2D animations, resulting in a sort of iconic charm. As a side note, they in fact did try to launch a sequel called Maplestory 2, which was sort of half 2D,  half 3D, but than ended up failing miserably and shut down within a couple years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying faithful to their art style and truly trying to perfect their aesthetics has really kept Maplestory going throughout the years. It’s similar reasoning to why the likes of Terraria and Stardew Valley are so popular, as one doesn’t necessarily have the mechanical skills to manage a 3D environment with lots of moving parts. As an example, one of my close friends starts to get headaches whenever he plays a more realistic game like Valorant, but has no problem with Terraria or Maplestory. Furthermore, their unique art style also contributes to the overall nostalgia of the game, as it’s reminiscent of a time gone by, where art styles were always so distinct and ever so unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s unfortunate that the performance of the game hasn’t scaled as well as the design - having the game initially developed in 2003 has led to a metric ton of problems regarding scalability and performance. Maplestory is currently running on 32 bit client, which greatly limits their possible ram consumption and also creates a lot of problem when it comes to storing larger numbers and leads to far more expensive computation requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-content&quot;&gt;The Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PSA: All of the following on content below is based on my experience in Reboot World in Maplestory, and I haven’t ever spent money on progression in this game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man, I am constantly surprised by how well Maplestory has kept its content going. Since I started playing in 2009, there have been so many game changing updates, from Big Bang, to Red, to Unleashed, and to the V update. The developers constantly release new content which completely change the flow of the game and the progression timeline. For example, back when I first started there were very few people who had crossed the level of 100, and I could probably count the number of people who hit 200 on two hands. Nowadays, the game doesn’t really start until you hit 200 or so, and in fact most people consider everything before 200 a tutorial of how the game works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that along with new content, they started to make that content more &lt;em&gt;attainable&lt;/em&gt;. The barrier to entry for new players hasn’t really changed all that much over the years - in fact while the level cap has been increased and more mechanics have been introduced, the game has done actually a wonderful job in explaining any of these new changes to players. Most people can get really far in the game just by playing a little over the span of a longer period of time, since the game really tends to reward daily/regular playtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I haven’t played a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of MMORPRG’s, I have played my fair share. I’ve played through PoE, a bit of ESO, Planetside 2, and a couple of the more minor ones. For each of those, the barrier to entry for insanely daunting. I remember looking at the HUGE map in Planetside 2 and being absolutely confused on where to start and what to do. Similarly, looking at the skill tree in PoE was really cool, but also really scary. The amount of guides I had to lookup for both was incredibly frustrating, since you shouldn’t have to look for external content in order to understand basic game mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the power creep in Maplestory is something that I absolutely adore. While it does have its fair share of problems which I’ll touch on it the next part, I do enjoy how easy it is to level up, get new gear, and get stronger overall. I recently started a new character about 3 or so months ago, and over the span of these 3 months I’ve been able to get to a point of killing nearly 60-70% of the bosses in the game either solo or with a group of friends. This was unthinkable for me until recently, and even two of my friends who had never played the game as a kid, have been able to reach the same state as me in a similar timeframe. Progression is quite cut and dry: you attain new gear, flame/cube it (essentially re-rolling stats), kill the next boss to get more gear. This all requires in game currency (at least on Reboot World), which is quite easy to obtain by just logging on for about 10 minutes or so every day (breaking a streak only affects the total amount linearly, that is there are no “streak” bonuses for logging on). The early-mid game flies by, and once you start reaching late game is where the grind really starts and progression slows down, but in all honesty this is the case with any MMO. Getting new gear is straightforward: there’s usually a guaranteed way to get the “next” item, but there are also ways to get it earlier by getting lucky through a drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these factors allow new and returning players alike to keep playing the game, never really getting bored since there’s always a guaranteed way to improve and get stronger if you put the time in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-daily-grind&quot;&gt;The Daily Grind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is a bit of a double-edged sword. On one hand, the game really rewards you for just doing something called “dailies”, which are daily quests that give you rewards that help you get stronger over time. This is quite beneficial for a lot of people, since just hopping on the game and doing dailies every day or whenever possible will guarantee growth over a longer period of time without having to constantly play the game for several hours at a time. On the other hand, this is time-gated by design. This means that although your character may get stronger through other means, these daily quests have a tendency to hold you back from progressing further. Sometimes the only way to get stronger is to just give it time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is kind of predatory if you think about it. By time-gating people, they’re forced to keep playing the game over time in order to get stronger, which when combined with the constant new content results in far greater amounts of player engagement. It’s genius in the sense that when a user hops on the game to do dailies, they may end up doing various other things in tandem since they also want to experience new content, which may then result in spending money on cosmetics or things like pets. Not doing dailies sort of feels like you’re losing possible progression due to the inherent opportunity cost: and a lot of times the game can come off as a part time job which is the exact opposite purpose that most people play the game for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this strategy has worked insanely well for them as it keeps retains players and keeps them engaged throughout the lifespan of the game. This, in recent years, has been the key to their success in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Maplestory has been part of my life for as long as I remember, and it truly holds a place in my heart. I’ll likely always return to it whenever I’m bored simply because of all the memories I’ve made with friends and even those I’ve made alone.  I do hope it continues to thrive since it truly has a lot of potential to improve and get better, and I also hope that this gave you a bit of insight on why it’s still alive today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pranav Krishnan</name></author><category term="thoughts" /><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html">Maplestory is a massively multiplayer online role playing game (MMORPG), that was originally created for Korea and was quickly followed up by a Global release. The main premise of the game is that you start by playing one of 40+ classes, working towards trying to get stronger and eventually teaming up with fellow players in order to take down the “big bad”. Classic MMORPG stuff. There’s a lot of training, bossing and tons of social interaction involved in the process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cyberpunk 2077: With Great Potential Comes Great Responsibility</title><link href="https://pkrshnan.com/cyberpunk-2077" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cyberpunk 2077: With Great Potential Comes Great Responsibility" /><published>2021-01-06T18:38:16-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-06T18:38:16-05:00</updated><id>https://pkrshnan.com/cyberpunk-2077</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pkrshnan.com/cyberpunk-2077">&lt;p&gt;Let me start with a bit of background about myself. I’ve played a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of video games, and without a doubt my favourite genre has to be RPGs.
Some of my favourites include The Witcher 3, Fallout: New Vegas, The Outer Worlds, and Skyrim. This being said, Cyberpunk 2077 has to be my most &lt;strong&gt;favourite one yet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 takes place in the year 2077 (well, duh) in Night City, a fictional place where cybernetic implants are commonplace and you can achieve anything you put your mind to.
You play as V, a mercenary trying to establish himself in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-world-design&quot;&gt;The World Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the world design, which is absolutely brilliant. Night City feels like the world described to me in Neuromancer, a cityscape set in a dystopian future where despite of all the radical technological improvements, simple human problems have not been solved.
Night City’s landscape is &lt;em&gt;breathtaking&lt;/em&gt;, and throughout my 70 (and counting) hours in the game, I was never once disappointed in the design.
I probably spent at least a good 2 hours in photo mode trying to take the perfect shot at various moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t without its fair share of problems however. While the city certainly has the futuristic theme to it, it also sort of feels “empty” at times. While there’s hundreds of people constantly walking and driving past you, none of them really feel like they’re real people, but rather complete robots when you attempt to speak to them. This establishes a rather common pattern in the game, the lack of good “AI”. Cars will randomly just stop behind you and wait if you stop in the middle of the lane, never attempting to pass you. People sometimes won’t even acknowledge you when you attempt to talk to them, or if they do, give a generic voice line. A lot of this reminded me of Skyrim, which came out almost 10 years ago now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to this, I have to give world design a &lt;strong&gt;8/10&lt;/strong&gt; since while the overall aesthetics are top notch, there are a lot of ways they could improve the “buzz” of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-writing&quot;&gt;The Writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the reason I love Cyberpunk 2077 so much is because of the story and the writing. It’s personally what I look for in an RPG, since that’s the whole point of role-playing. I want to &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; in the characters and the story, feel like I’m part of all of it. This is where the game really shines.
There are so many beautifully crafted characters, each with their own storyline and personalities. It’s the first time for me where I truly felt attached to certain characters (even Witcher 3 felt rather forced in this aspect), and it’s wonderful to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every side mission has a lot of depth to it, exploring yet another person’s way of life in the mess that is Night City. Whether it be a monk who truly believes in anti-violence, or the nomad who simply wants the best for her family, they all have a backstory that you want to know about.
Even gigs, which are your usual fetch quests, tend to have something more to them. A story behind the heist, reasoning for it and optional background lore that explains the reason for the hire if you’re interested. It isn’t some usual “I dropped this in a cave”, or “I had it stolen from me”. This being said, I do wish it was a lot more like the Witcher contracts in the Witcher 3, which required you to do a lot of research on how to fight the particular monster. These felt far harder and much more realistic, compared to Cyberpunk’s easy fetch quests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think the writing and story are a &lt;strong&gt;9/10&lt;/strong&gt;, missing a point solely due to the rather mundane difficulty of the gigs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-combat&quot;&gt;The Combat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to quickly cover the combat in this game. Personally, I love the sheer number of options you have in fights. There are so many different and amazing playstyles, whether it be the bloodshed samurai, or the silent and undetected assassin, or even the netrunner who can take down an entire building without ever stepping inside. The skill tree is absolutely bonkers, and it reminds me of that of modded Skyrim, specifically mods like Requiem, Ordinator or even Perkus Maximus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you combine that with the sheer number of cybernetic implants and their respective modifiers, you’re able to pick a unique build that suits your character archetype. Heck, there’s even a way to travel faster than any car in the game by just running and hopping using implants. It’s wonderful talking to my friends and going over the various builds we use, as there are almost an infinite number of ways to play this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing is without it’s flaws however. The biggest one is once again, the poor enemy AI. As the game progresses, a lot of enemies feel very weak and simple. There are no crazy enemy netrunners who can hack you back, or mantis blade users who run after you, or even patrols who aren’t completely inept at checking their surroundings.
While I certainly have a ton of fun taking fights, they feel like a joke at times (even at harder difficulties).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this being said, I personally find the combat fun enough to warrant a &lt;strong&gt;8/10&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t find it to be the focus of the game, but I certainly wish it was a bit more polished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bugs&quot;&gt;The Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s a Cyberpunk 2077 review without mentioning the hilarity of bugs present in this game?
I feel bad since while I personally only experience a few visual bugs, I never experience anything truly game breaking, likely due to the fact that I played on a reasonably performant PC. I can’t really comment on the bugs due to this reason, but I certainly empathize with the poor experiences people have attempting to play this game on original PS4s and Xbox Ones.
However, this is nothing that’s not fixable after launch. There have already been quite a few patches, and a few major ones yet to come in January/February of 2021.
An important thing to note is The Witcher 3 also had its fair share of bugs and problems, but were quickly rectified following the launch, as well as plenty of free DLC to compensate for the troubles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-verdict&quot;&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 is a game with immense potential. Leading up to the launch, people referred to the game as the defining moment in RPG history; the next generation of role playing games.
Expectations were pushed higher and higher, leading to unmatchable expectations. Despite my personal reasonable expectations for the game, I did feel a little let down. There was a lot that could have been improved, from certain gameplay skips and the whole slew of bugs in the game, to the clear lack of good AI.
It’s still one of my all-time favourites, simply due to how good it &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game certainly has the potential to improve and actually become one of the defining titles of 2021 (when it should have been released). The only question is, will CDPR actually deliver?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pranav Krishnan</name></author><category term="thoughts" /><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html">Let me start with a bit of background about myself. I’ve played a lot of video games, and without a doubt my favourite genre has to be RPGs. Some of my favourites include The Witcher 3, Fallout: New Vegas, The Outer Worlds, and Skyrim. This being said, Cyberpunk 2077 has to be my most favourite one yet.</summary></entry></feed>